Career Highlights

Left Turn Only: Lead Developer Austin, TX

March 2016-Present

As a technical visionary of Left Turn Only, I actualize business requirements internally and for clients. My role at Left Turn Only is close to that of a CTO that simultaneously is looking for new business opportunities, researching that viability along with overseeing all technical projects that come through the business. Since joining LTO, the web dev department now contributes to over 60% of revenue, and is doubling its revenue every 2 quarters. I initiated a R&D department to build a 5 year plan of sustainability for the business.

XTech Staffing: Programmer Austin, TX

July-Oct 2017

At XTech, I was instrumental in growing the marketing and operations department capabilities. The marketing outreach increased 3x during my time, while the operations were streamlined by migrating to a new system with multiple API integrations, increasing efficiency by approx 10%. I expanded the website for new AdWord campaigns generating a total of 20 new pages, including 3rd party integrations requiring custom Wordpress plugins. I also built out 25+ business analytics dashboards and graphs for a new CRM/ATS full pipeline business system; as well as trained 12 employees on its use.

Querium: Programmer and Math Specialist Austin, TX

April 2016-July 2017

The resident expert in Mathematics and Curriculum, I was responsible for verifying the accuracy and completeness of the AI Virtual Math tutor. I redesigned the Git Flow for the AI Engineering team, supported and contributed to the automated testing suite, wrote rules for the AI in Mathematica and wrote over 200 math questions for AI testing.

Social Solutions: Software Engineer 1 Austin, TX

June 2014-Dec 2015

As a Software Engineer, I was responsible for at least 1 new feature per release cycle following the SDLC. I also supported QA and Product departments with documentation and additional testing. I worked daily in a MVC design pattern using RESTful deployment. I contributed 8 new features to the product and fixed over 100 major and minor issues in the codebase.

Education

University of Minnesota: BA in Mathematics University of Minnesota: M Ed in Math Education

SKILLS PROFILE	
PHP [Zend, Wordpress, Laravel]	4 years
HTML/MarkupLanguage [HTML5 Canvas, LaTeX, YML, MathML]	4 years
Javascript [Mootools, jQuery, React, Webpack, Yarn, Nodejs]	3 years
CSS [Bootstrap, SCSS, Grunt]	3 years
Databases [MySql, PHPMyAdmin, Firebase, MongoDB, Query Optimization]	4 years
Dev Workflow [Agile, Scrum/Standups, Pair Programming, Code Review, Ticketing, Trello, Jira]	3 years
Dev Tools [CLI, Git, WP CLI, Linux, Atom, Bash, SSH, FTP, Vagrant, OSX]	5 years
Data Science [data cleanup and organization, representations, inference testing, Python, R]	2 years
Digital Marketing [Schema Markup, Marketing Automations, API Integrations, Large Scale Email Marketing, Brand Identity Management]	2 years
Cloud Computing [Google Cloud Platform, AWS, Docker]	1 year